Berliner Gramophone Disc Collection
Yale University Music Library
Berliner Gramophone Disc Collection
1887-1912
MSS 142
Yale University Music Library
17
17 Boxes. Berliner Gramophone Discs. All discs are 7 inch in diameter except where noted.
Digitized Collection
This collection is fully digitized.
- Recordings, Series I
  - The Chalatan March; Sousa's Band; Arthur Pryor, cond., 1899 April 22; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523241)
    Scope and Contents
    Disc No. 076. Book: "Flirtation" (Steck)
  - The Chalatan March; Sousa's Band; Arthur Pryor, cond., 1899 April 22; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523258)
    Disc No. 076.
  - The Thunderer March; Sousa's Band, 1897 October; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523266)
    Disc No. 30x. New York. Henry Higgin, cond[?]
  - Romance for Trombone; Military Band, 1897 May 27; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523274)
    Disc No. 62z. Washington D.C.
  - The Bride Elect March; Sousa's Band., 1898 February 3; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523282)
    Disc No. 92.
  - Star Spangled Banner; Sousa's Band., 1898 April 7; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523290)
    Disc No. 103y. New York.
  - Songs of Scotland; Sousa's Band; Arthur Pryor, cond., 1898 September 2; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523308)
    Disc No. 141. New York.
  - Sally in our Alley; George J. Gaskin, 1895 October 31; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523316)
    Disc No. 162. New York.
  - Russian Fantaie; W. Paris Chambers, 1896 May 6; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523324)
    Disc No. 230. Philadelphia.
  - Danse Unique (Leo Prince); Piano Solo., 1896 April 28; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523332)
    Disc No. 255. Anon. piano
  - Geisterfunken (waldteufel). anon. piano, 1892 November 17; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523340)
    Disc No. 256.
  - Whistling Medley; Milton M. Clark, 1898 March; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523357)
    Disc No. 427.
  - Robin Hood: Oh, Promise Me (Scott De Koven); Jessie Bartlett Davis, 1898 May 3; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523365)
    Disc No. 552z. New York.
  - For the Nursery; Russell Hunting, 1896 May 8; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523373)
    Disc No. 604w.
  - Casey as Chairman of Mugwump Club; Russell Hunting, 1897 March 20; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523381)
    Disc No. 615. Washington, DC.
  - Piano Sale; George Gaham, 1896 May 26; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523399)
    Disc No. 644.
  - Talk on Money; George Gaham, 1896 June 2; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523407)
    Disc No. 645z.
  - Hiram's Visit to New York; Russell Hunting., 1897 January 24; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523415)
    Disc No. 667. New York.
  - Piccolo Solo; Mr. George Schweinfest., undated; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523423)
    Disc No. 892. Patrol Comique. Montreal, Canada.
  - On Liberty; Robert G. Ingersoll, 1897 December 31; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523431)
    Disc No. 695. New York.
  - La Marseillaise; Sig. A. del Campo, 1896 May 4; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523449)
    Disc No. 901. Ferruccio Giannini.
  - Il Trovatore - "Di quella pira"; F. Girannini; arr. E. + Pf., 1896 May 7; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523456)
    Disc No. 903.
  - Rock of Ages (Toplady-Hastings); Steve Porter, 1897 July 30; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523464)
    Disc No. 917y. New York.
  - Mascagni: Cavalleria Rusticanna - "Viva il Vino"; Sig. F. A. Giannini, 1898 May 31; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523472)
    Disc No. 932x. New York.
  - The Wizard of the Nile; Cohen Sitting Alone, 1896 April 18; 1; This disc is damaged. A small section on the outer edge of the disc has chipped off. The broken section is missing. (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523480)
    Disc No. 953. Damaged on top. The Wizard of the Nile: Star Light, Star Bright (Smith-Herbert).
  - Verdi: Rigoletto - "La donn à mobile"; F. Giannini, arr. w/ piano, 1896 January 21; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523498)
    Disc No. 967. Recorded in Philadelphia.
  - The Palms (Faure); Ferruccio Giannini, 1896 April 15; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523506)
    Disc No. 971z.
  - Verdi: Rigoletto - "Questa o quella"; F. Giannini, arr. w/ piano, 1896 April 15; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523514)
    Disc No. 983. Recorded in Philadelphia.
  - The Holy City (Weatherly - Adams); Ferruccio Giannini, 1896 April 10; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523522)
    Disc No. 986.
  - The Sweetest Story Ever Told (Stults); George J. Gaskin, 1896 November 16; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523530)
    Disc No. 996y.
  - Dinorah Romance: Sig. A. del Campo, 1897 August 13; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523548)
    Disc No. 1108. New York.
  - La Golondrina (Cancion Cantada); Signor Adamini, undated; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523555)
    Disc No. 1219. Spanish.
  - Caramba (Cancion, Cantada); Sig. Adamini, undated; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523563)
    Disc No. 1243z. Spanish.
  - Santa Lucia (Cottrau); Ferruccio Giannini, 1896 November 17; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523571)
    Disc No. 1617.
  - Schubert: Schwanengesang, D. 957 "Ständchen"; Giannini., 1898 November; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523589)
    Disc No. 1920z. Sung in Italian with piano. Abridged.
  - Steig auf die Alm; Graus Mountain Choir Quartette, 1897 June 28; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523597)
    Disc No. 3194. New York.
  - Melba Waltz; Miss. Helen Jenynge, undated; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523605)
    Disc No. 3660x. Disc - Arditi: Se saran rose. Edith Helana with piano. In Italian. Words by Pietro Mazzini.
  - Prayer and Air from Det Freischutz; violin solo by Miss. Jennie Hoyle of Sousa's Band, undated; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523613)
    Disc No. 4807. Disc - Leise, leise, fromme wiese; arr. violin and piano.
  - Sermon on the Mount spoken by Rev. T. de Witt Talmage - Matthew V, 3-11., 1898 April 8; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523621)
    Disc No. 5009. Washington, D.C.
  - The Lord's Prayer and 23rd Psalm spoken by Rev. T. de Witt Talmage, 1898 April 8; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523639)
    Disc No. 5010. Washington, D.C.
  - Toreador de Carmen: B(ernard) Bégué, 1899 September 16; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523647)
    Disc No. 0493r. French.
  - Abenstern, 'Tannhauser'; Carl Bernhard, 1899 October 13; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523654)
    Disc No. 0633(q). German.
  - Prologue, 'I Pagliacci'; E. Francisco, undated; 1 (Box 728, Item barcode 39002126523662)
    Disc No. 01120(p). Italian.
  - Grand Aria (Semiramide): Chant avec piano: Sung by Roma, 1899 January 29; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006222)
    Disc No. 3072
  - Annie Laurie: Sung by Madame [illeg] Roma, 1901 March 9; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006230)
    Disc No. 3067x
  - Serenata Braga with obligato: sung by Miss E. Clegg, 1898 November 10; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006248)
    Disc No. 3046
  - London Bridge [Molloy?]: sung by Miss E. Clegg, 1908 October 25; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006255)
    Disc No. 3035
  - Dal Polska: Swedish Song: sung by Miss Bell; Mme Ranske, 1898 October 6; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006263)
    Disc No. 3030
  - The Wild Rose: Heidenroslein: Schubert: sung by Miss E. Clegg, 1898 October 21; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006271)
    Disc No. 3026
  - Ave Maria: Schubert: Sung by Miss E. Clegg, 1898 October 11; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006289)
    Disc No. 3023
  - The Irish Emigrant (Barker): sung by Mr. John McCormack, 1904 September 23; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006297)
    Disc No. 3-2525
  - When Shall the Day Break in Erin (Fox): sung by Mr. John McCormack, 1904 September 23; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006305)
    Disc No. 3-2520
  - Killarney (Balfe): sung by Mr. John McCormack, 1904 September 23; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006313)
    Disc No. 3-2514
  - Killiecrankie: sung by Mr. Harry Lauder, 1903 December 28; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006321)
    Disc No. 2-2421
  - The John Bull Store (Robert Eden): sung by Mr. David Brazell, 1903 October 19; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006339)
    Disc No. 2-2354
  - Archie "Toreador": sung by Mr. Henry Lytton, 1902 May; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006347)
    Disc No. 2-2137
  - Me and Mrs. Brown "Country Girl": sung by Mr. Henry Lytton, 1902 June; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006354)
    Disc No. 2-2136
  - It suddenly dawned upon me: sung by Mr. George Robey, 1902 June; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006362)
    Disc No. 2-2120
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    2
    Other Finding Aids
    1901
  - When I marry Amelia "Toreador": sung by Mr. Henry Lytton, 1902 May; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006370)
    Disc No. 2-2112
  - Peace Peace: "Country Girl": sung by Mr. Henry Lytton, 1902 May; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006388)
    Disc No. 2-2111
  - Peace Peace: "Country Girl": sung by Mr. Henry Lytton, 1902 May; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006396)
  - Everybody [illeg] good to me: sung by Mr. Henry Lytton, 1902 May; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006404)
    Disc No. 2-2110
  - Everybody's awfully good to me: "Toreador": Sung by Mr. Henry Lytton, 1902; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006412)
  - In the Kings name stand: "Country Girl": sung by Mr. William Paull, 1902; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006420)
    Disc No. 2-2096
  - The Holy City: Stephen Adams: sung by Mr. Albert Pearce, 1901–1902; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006438)
    Disc No. 2-2085
  - I'll sing thee songs of Araby (Clay): sung by Mr. Albert Pearce, undated; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006446)
    Disc No. 2-2083
  - Friend and Lover (Landon Ronald): sung by Mr. Joseph Mara accompanied by Mr. Landon Ronald, 1901 December; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006453)
    Disc No. 2-2062
  - An Irish Birthday: Ronald, 1901 December; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006461)
    Disc No. 2-2061
  - Song that reached my heart: sung by Mr. William Paull, 1901; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006479)
    Disc No. 2-2045
  - Two eyes of Blue "Silver Slipper" (Leslie Stuart): sung by Mr. Louis Breeze, 1901; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006487)
    Disc No. 2-2040
  - The girl of my heart: sung by Mr. [illeg] Russell with orchestra, 1900 November 27; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006495)
    Disc No. 2984
  - Jack's the Boy: Geisha: Sung by Mr. Scott Russell with orchestra, 1900 March 12; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006503)
    Disc No. 2923
  - Star of my soul: Geisha: Sung by Mr. wells Page with orchestra accompaniment, 1900; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006511)
    Disc No. 2964
  - Freedom: Greek Slave: sung by Mr. [Conway?] Dixon, 1900 December 28; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006529)
    Disc No. 2962
  - Death of [Nelson?]: [Braham?]: sung by Mr. Wells Page with orchestra, 1900; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006537)
    Disc No. 2955
  - Burlesque on "Pretty Maidens": [Floradora?]: Sung by Mr. Louis Bradfield, 1900 October 20; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006545)
    Disc No. 2935
  - The Girl of My Heart (Greek [Stare?]): Sung by Louis Breeze, 1900 September 26; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006552)
    Disc No. 2925
  - Whistling Loon: sung by B. Shepard; whistled by B. Earl, 1901 January 2; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006560)
    Disc No. 2476
  - Is Yer Mammie Always Wid Yer: sung by Eugene Stratton, 1899; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006578)
    Disc No. 2399
  - Is Yer Mammie Always Wid Yer?: sung by Eugene Stratton, 1899; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006586)
  - Les Enfants ([Massenet?]): chant avec piano: J. Thomas, 1912 September 8; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006594)
    Disc No. 2368
  - Just one Girl: sung by Mr. A. Scott Russell, 1899 January 2; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006602)
    Disc No. 2349
  - Saturnalia ([Greek?] Slave): sung by [M.?] Scott Russell & Chorus, 1899 January 18; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006610)
    Disc No. 2338
  - Sweethearts: sung by Mr. Will Page, undated; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006628)
    Disc No. 2201
  - Legende: La Mascotte: chante par [Miss?] Marty des Minstrels Parisiens, 1898 December 3; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006636)
    Disc No. 2173
  - La Priere Guillaume Tell: chante par Mons. Marty, 1898 December 3; 1; Item not digitized. There is a large surface imperfection on this disc; groove is damaged causing incessant skipping. (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006644)
    Disc No. 2163
  - Les Rameaux: chante aveg piano: J. Thomas, 1899 January 7; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006651)
    Disc No. 2153
  - The Whistling Loon: sung by Burt Shepard; whistled by Burt Earle, 1901 June 2; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006669)
    Disc No. 2143
  - Take a Pair of Sparlking Eyes: H. Scott Russell, 1898 August 19; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006677)
    Disc No. 2006
  - Jack's the Boy: sung by H. Scott Russell, 1899 January 14; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006685)
    Disc No. 2005
  - Jack's the Boy: H. Scott Russell, 1898 August 19; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006693)
  - American Patrol: played by Sousa's Band, undated; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006701)
    Disc No. 2-377
  - Kunst Leben Valses (Artist's Life): Trocadero Orchestra, 1898; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006719)
    Disc No. 537
  - Stephanie [Gavotte?]: Trocadero Orchestra, undated; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006735)
    Disc No. 518
  - Broken gramophone disc: tenor with chorus, undated; 1 (Box 730, Item barcode 39002125006727)
    Disc No. 8-26423
  - Dadra: sung by Banni Jan, undated; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006743)
    Disc No. 2-12452
  - Puzzle Plate, 1900 January 20; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006750)
    Disc No. 9317
  - Puzzle Plate, 1901 January 21; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006768)
    Disc No. 9317F
  - Christy Minstrels: introducing Elsie from Chelsea, 1899; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006776)
    Disc No. 9284X
  - Puzzle Plate: comic routine: piano solo; male singer with piano, 1901 January; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006784)
    Disc No. 9317A
  - Mazurka Souvenir de Posen (Wieniawski): played by Mr. Bernard Carrodus, undated; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006792)
    Disc No. 7925
  - Simple Aveu (Thome): played by Mr. Bernard Carrodus, undated; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006800)
    Disc No. 7924
  - Hearts & Flowers (Tobani.): played by Mr. Bernard Carrodus, undated; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006818)
    Disc No. 7923
  - Pizzicata [from?] Sylvia: violin solo by Mr. J. Jacobs, 1899 June 4; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006826)
    Disc No. 7921
  - Norwegian Bridal March (Greig): played by Mr. Landen Ronald, 1900 October 25; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006834)
    Disc No. 5521
  - Excerpt from L'Enfant Prodigue: played by Mr. Landen Ronald, 1900 October 20; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006842)
    Disc No. 5519
  - Little Dolly Daydream: played by the composer Leslie Stuart, 1899 October 1; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006859)
    Disc No. 5509
  - Soldiers of the Queen: Fantasia: played by the composer Leslie Stuart, 1899 September 1; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006867)
    Disc No. 5508
  - Blue Bells of Scotland: cornet solo: Mr. Ed E. Bates, 1898 September 17; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006875)
    Disc No. 5033
  - How Sweet the Name of Jesus Sounds: Church Choir, 1900 August 28; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006883)
    Disc No. 4757
  - Tell me pretty maiden: Floradora: Sung by the members of the Lyric Theatre: Accompanied by the composer, 1900 October 5; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006891)
    Disc No. 4524
  - The Emperor's Own: from Opera ["San doy?"]: Daly's Theatre Chorus, 1900 September 4; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006909)
    Disc No. 4519
  - Rhoda and her Pagoda: [San Joy?]: sung by Miss Maud Marsden and Chorus, 1900 August 28; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006917)
    Disc No. 4517
  - Quarrelling "Country Girl": sung by Miss Henri & Henry Lytton, 1902 June; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006925)
    Disc No. 4084
  - Little [Chinee?] Maid from the opera "San Joy": sung by Miss Marsden and Mr. Henry, 1900 September 12; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006933)
    Disc No. 4069
  - Cosi Fan Tutte: duo: Mlle. Louise Dousle and Mlle. Jeanne Dousle, 1899; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006941)
    Disc No. 4067
  - Two little Chicks: "Country Girl": sung by Miss Henri & Henry Lytton, undated; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006958)
    Disc No. 4062-II
  - Finale du Dernier Acte (Faust): chante avec piano: Les Troubadours Toulousains, 1899 January 25; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006966)
    Disc No. 4053
  - Two Little Chicks: "Country Girl": sung by Miss Henri & Henry Lytton, 1902; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006974)
    Disc No. 4062
  - La Toulousaine: Chant avec piano: Les Troubadours Toulousains, 1899 January 25; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006982)
    Disc No. 4048
  - Exelsior ([Ealfe?]): sung by Wills Page & William [Paul?], 1902; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125006990)
    Disc No. 4047-II
  - La Marche des Tambourins: chant avec piano: Les Troubadours Toulousains, 1899 January 25; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007006)
    Disc No. 4047
  - "When we are married": sung by Mr. Montague Borwell and Miss. W. Marwood, 1899; 1; Item not digitized. Groove is damaged; stylus won't advance even with physical manipulation. (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007014)
    Disc No. 4012-XX
  - The Better Land (Cowen): sung by Miss Kate Cove, 1904 September 2; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007022)
    Disc No. 3368
  - Comin thro the Rye: Edith Helena, undated; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007030)
    Disc No. 3348
  - Damon: sung by Miss Perceval Allen, undated; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007048)
    Disc No. 3318
  - The Four Leafed Shamrock (Willeby): sung by Miss Perceval Allen, undated; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007055)
    Disc No. 3316
  - Under the Deodah: sung by Miss Henri, undated; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007063)
    Disc No. 3247
  - Violets (Ellen Wright): sung by Madame Kirkby Lunn, 1902 February; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007071)
    Disc No. 3240
  - One Spring Morning (Nevins): Sung by Mme. Kirkby Lunn, 1902 February; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007089)
    Disc No. 3239x
  - Spring is Here (E. Dicks): sung by Miss Perceval Allen, undated; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007097)
    Disc No. 3237
  - Air des Bijoux: Jewel Song: Faust: sung by Miss Marie Tempest, 1901 March 18; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007105)
    Disc No. 3233
  - Scenes That Are Brightest: Maritana: sung by Madame Roma, 1901 March 13; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007113)
    Disc No. 3231
  - The Jewel of Asia: "Geisha": sung by Miss Marie Tempest, 1901 March 8; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007121)
    Disc No. 3229x
  - The Jewel of Asia: "Geisha": sung by Miss Marie Tempest, 1901 March 8; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007139)
    Disc No. 3229
  - Little Bird So Sweetly Singing: sung by Miss Kate Cove with flute obligato, 1901 March 14; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007147)
    Disc No. 3224
  - Queen of the Philippine Islands: Floradora: sung by Miss Ada Reeves: accompanied by Mr. Paul Rubens, 1900 October 20; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007154)
    Disc No. 3209
  - Flow on From the [Belle?] of New York: sung by Miss Edna May, 1900 May 8; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007162)
    Disc No. 3192X
  - Old Folks at Home (Swannee River): sung by [Mme?] Benzing, 1900 August 29; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007170)
    Disc No. 3137
  - Les Noces de Jeannette: chant avec accompaniment de flute: Ellen [Bearl Yan?], 1899 March 18; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007188)
    Disc No. 3106
  - L'Eclat de Rire: chant avec piano: Ellen Beach [Lane?], 1899 March 19; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007196)
    Disc No. 3097
  - Son Vergin Vezzosa (J. Puritani): chante avec piano: Roma, 1899; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007204)
    Disc No. 3081
  - Il Bacio: The Kiss: Sung by Madame Roma, 1901 March 13; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007212)
    Disc No. 3075X
  - Il Bacio: chant avec piano: sung by Roma, 1899 January 27; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007220)
    Disc No. 3075
  - Roberto H. Diavolo: sung by Madame Roma, 1901 March 13; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007246)
    Disc No. 3073X
  - Robert Le Diable: chant avec piano: Robert the Devil: sung by Roma, 1899 January 27; 1 (Box 731, Item barcode 39002125007238)
    Disc No. 3073
  - Bengali Song, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007253)
    Disc No. 13035
  - Mahamedan Song, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007261)
    Disc No. 13038
  - Bengali Song, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007279)
    Disc No. 13227
  - Bengali Chorus, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007287)
    Disc No. 14547
  - Japanese Song, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007295)
    Disc No. 13283
  - Japanese Song with Samisen, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007303)
    Disc No. 13291
  - Glinka: Ruslan i diudruila, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007311)
    Disc No. 20065
  - M.M. Chuprynnikov and K.T. Serebriakov, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007329)
    Disc No. 20611
  - G.A. Morskoi: Prigozhavy, "Ne govori, chto molodost' sgubila", undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007337)
    Disc No. 22152
  - P.D. Oslov Gounod; Faust; Mefistofele's Arioso "Spustilas t'ma", undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007345)
    Disc No. 22116
  - Kochetovoi "Noch, tepla i volslebnaia snietit luna" ("Night is warm, fabulous moonlight", undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007352)
    Disc No. 22251x
  - Florjanski; Aria: "Oh, Our Lord", undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007360)
    Disc No. 22184
  - Rubinstein, "Ne plach' ditia" ("Don't cry, child"), undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007378)
    Disc No. 22254
  - Russian Tenor, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125667718)
    Disc No. 22261
  - Russian Tenor, 1901; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125667726)
    Disc No. 22262
  - Eugenii Oniegin: V Vashem Domie "In Your House", undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007386)
    Disc No. 22264
  - Lenskii's Aria, 1901; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125008244)
    Disc No. 22291
  - L.V. Sobinoo, 1901; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125008251)
    Disc No. 22320
  - V.S. Sharonoff, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007394)
    Disc No. 22327
  - Rechitativi Kavat. Kniazia Vladimira N.V. Sobinov, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007402)
    Disc No. 22333
  - Russian Tenor, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125008269)
    Disc No. 22338
  - Russian Baritone, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125008277)
    Disc No. 22367
  - "Trubadur" Verdi A.M. Labinskii, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007428)
    Disc No. 22369
  - Tarulla Valiulin "Makkup" "Apagom", undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007436)
    Disc No. 22380
  - Russian Baritone, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007691)
    Disc No. 22401
  - A.M. Labinski Urangel "Kakaia noch" ("What a Night"), undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007444)
    Disc No. 22408
  - Severski Gypsy Song: "Otoidi" ("go away"), undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007451)
    Disc No. 22424
  - Severski: N.G. Seuerski Zeller "Pro da vets petits" (vogellandler) walz, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007469)
    Disc No. 22427
  - Tartakov: Davydov "Ty ne sprashivai" ("Dont ask"); I.V. Tartakov, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007477)
    Disc No. 22451
  - Epitalama iz op. "Nevon" Rulo. I.V. Tartakov, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007485)
    Disc No. 22452
  - I.V. Tartakov: Carmen, Torreador's Soy, undated; 1 (Box 732, Item barcode 39002125007493)
    Disc No. 22469